JOSHUA SARDINHA

COMPUTER ENGINEER, SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



- Brazilian
- +1 (480) 796-0097
- joshua.sardinha@gmail.com

SKILLS

ENGINEERING

- IoT Development
- Assembly Coding
- Embedded systems

SW DEVELOPMENT

- Mobile Development
- Web Development
- Server Development
- LLM Integration
- UX Metrification
- Neural Networks

DESIGN

- UI Designer
- Vector Art Drawing
- Product Designer

MANAGEMENET

- Strategic Planning
- High Adaptability
- Productivity Assessment
- Conflict Resolution

EDUCATION

 Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

> Unicamp - Universidade Estadual de Campinas

2015 - 2019

PROFILE

A dedicated Computer Engineer with 9 years of experience in a diverse range of software development within renowned companies, research institutes, and personal projects.

Has significant expertise in developing Front-End software with Android, Flutter, and React, as well as experience with Server development and DevOps from early implementation to production. Also possesses a track record of structuring strategic business solutions with statistics and systems to successfully hack company growth.

Values clear communication, integrity, and meaningful and purposeful relations. Strives to motivate others, build a strong network, and generate a positive influence around himself. Adaptability, empathy, and focus are some of his strongest traits.

EXPERIENCE

DIRECTOR OF OPERATIONS

Jul 2024 - Current

NATIONAL NINER

Led day-to-day operations with a focus on designing, implementing, and continuously optimizing internal processes. Oversaw company finances, managed client and associate agreements, and handled immigration petition cases in collaboration with attorneys and paralegals. Managed client communications and contributed to marketing, sales campaigns, and business development efforts.

Additionally, developing an Al-driven product aimed at making legal services more accessible and user-friendly.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb 2022 - Jan 2024

SENDIT / ICONIC HEARTS

Contributed to the development of a wide range of features across mobile social media applications. Worked on integrations with Snapchat and Instagram, implemented payment systems, built user profile and communication tools, and developed video content features, among others.

JOSHUA SARDINHA

COMPUTER ENGINEER, SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

EXPERTISE

EXPERIENCE

(CONTINUED)

TECHNICAL

- Flutter
- Android
- React
- Node Express
- AWS EC2, RDS, Lambda
- Clean Architecture
- Test Driven Development
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe XD

LANGUAGE

- PORTUGUESE NATIVE
- **ENGLISH FLUENT**
- SPANISH INTERMEDIATE

INTERESTS

HOBBIE

- Cycling
- Swimming
- Skydiving
- Piano
- Gaming
- Grilling burgers

SOCIAL

- Teachina
- Event managing
- Social Work (Watoto)

CO-FOUNDER AND CTO

LHP SERVICES

• May 2021 - Jul 2022

Founded LHP Services with the intention to serve the LHPilots community with a greater range of services. Developed a membership system for the pilots, provided a range of services to ensure the lean and swift flow of the EB-2 Visa Consultation services offered, and currently optimizes company growth through analytics and consumer-centric strategies.

CO-FOUNDER

• Jan 2021 - Current

LHPILOTS

Founded LHPilots as a community of European pilots in the post-pandemic scenario to unite the professionals, facilitate training and deliver job offers. Created a pilot platform for mutual contact, exclusive access to Computer Based Training (CBTs), and hiring opportunities offered by airlines.

CO-FOUNDER AND DEVELOPER

Mar 2020 - Feb 2021

DELIVERTÉ

Developed Deliverté from scratch. Designed it to make travels more efficient and to allow products to be taken with moving travelers, who would receive their fee for the items. Assembled the product mock-up and validation, designed the UX and the UI, developed the client and server codes, built a CI/CD base, completed the App and Play Store internal accounts, successfully deployed the production app, and integrated new updates. Deliverté was frozen for a year and development is being restarted in January 2022.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

• Feb 2020 - Dec 2020

ELDORADO RESEARCH INSTITUTE

Built a diverse range of solutions for different external companies as a developer and software consultant. Developed user portals for partner NGOs, websites for smaller projects, a PWA for a startup, a project architecture for a bank app, and Alexa apps for larger companies.

JOSHUA SARDINHA

COMPUTER ENGINEER, SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

EXPERIENCE

(CONTINUED)

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

• Aug 2018 - Feb 2020

ELDORADO RESEARCH INSTITUTE

Developed an Android application with chat, Push to Talk, radio, task management, and workday features for Motorola. Developed the latest stages of the chat with the user profile picture, a new Live Location feature using Google Maps APIs and a UI revamp. Had crucial participation in the migration for the compilation to x64 architectures. Implemented the interface and functionalities for the new app branch which would handle workday and tasks management.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

• Jul 2018 - Aug 2018

MOTOROLA

Responsible for the client-side of a pilot Android app developed in association with the internal Motorola Tools team to support another working team of Motorola.